(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
アルバム 徹底解説
Album Thorough Explanation
ミニ ライブもあるよ
There's a mini live too
2024 11.6 on sale
アルバム発売日だ！おどれー！
It's album release day! Dance!
おおっ！
Whoa!
殴ってる、殴ってる！
She's punching, she's punching!
何を殴ってるの？
What are you punching?
見えない敵がいるなぁ！
There's an invisible enemy!
ビビ、ビビさん？
Bibi, Bibi-san?
あ、どこだここ？
Ah, where am I?
どこだここ？
Where am I?
うわぁー！
Uwaa!
ヘイ！ヘイ！
Hey! Hey!
何？何？
What? What?
助けてー！
Help me!
何このパート？何してたらいいの？
What is this part? What should I be doing?
うわぁー！
Uwaa!
やだー！何やってんのー！
Nooo! What are you doing?!
あー、これやらなきゃ…
Ah, I have to do this...
被っちゃう、被っちゃう。めちゃ被るよ。
I'm overlapping, I'm overlapping. Really overlapping.
被ってた、被ってた。
We were overlapping.
11月6日水曜日は、私たちReGLOSSの
Wednesday, November 6th, is our ReGLOSS
ファーストアルバム発売記念日なので、踊り狂っておりました。
first album release anniversary, so we've been dancing like crazy.
大丈夫？
You okay?
ちょっと座りたいんだけど。
I want to sit down for a bit.
ちょっと待って。ヤバい人がいました。
Wait a second. There was a crazy person.
えー、アルバムリリース日ですけど、
Uh, it's the album release day, but
皆さんどうですか？実感ありますか？
how about you all? Does it feel real?
実感？
Feel real?
今それどころじゃないよ！
I'm in no state for that right now!
死ぬ死ぬ、死ぬ死ぬ！
I'm gonna die, I'm gonna die!
お疲れ様です。
Good work.
配信されちゃったよね！
It's been released!
配信されちゃったよねー！
そうだね。
That's right.
みんな聴いたよねー！
Everyone listened to it!
実感あるね。
It feels real.
ちょっと1回座るか。
Let's sit down for a moment.
しんどい、しんどい。
Tired, tired.
すごいリリカさんがちょっとあの、おじい…
Ririka-san looks a bit like an old...
大丈夫か？
You okay?
嘘じゃない、嘘じゃない。
No lie, no lie.
嘘じゃないけど座ろうかな。
It's not a lie, but let's sit down.
頑張ったんだよ。
I worked hard.
楽しかった。
That was fun.
ちょっと目が覚めたわ。
I've woken up a bit.
良かった。
Good.
ちょっと目が覚めた。
Woken up a bit.
はい、ということでございまして、
Yes, so,
冒頭ね、踊り狂っておりましても
despite dancing like crazy at the beginning,
お一人バテバテの人がおりますけれども。
there's one person who is completely exhausted.
え？誰？
Eh? Who?
誰ー？
Who?
誰だ？
Who's that?
お一人だけバテバテ。
Just one person is exhausted.
バテバテのやついんの？この中に。
Is there an exhausted one here?
バテバテのやついんの？
Is there an exhausted one?
誰だ？
Who is it?
初っ端から。
Right from the start.
しょぼ。
Lame.
あなただよ！
It's you!
困ったな。
Goodness.
えーということでございまして、
Uh, so,
ホロライブデバイスチャンネルをご覧の皆様こんばんは。
good evening to everyone watching the Hololive DEV_IS channel.
えー本日MCを担当いたします、
Uh, I'm the MC for today,
儒烏風亭らでんでございます。よろしくお願いします。
Juufuutei Raden. Nice to meet you.
本日はですね、アルバム発売日ということもありまして、
Today is our album release day,
もう「THE・音楽番組」的なね、感じで、
so in a "THE Music Program" style,
私たちのファーストアルバムを徹底解剖していきます。
we're going to thoroughly analyze our first album.
アーティストモードな私たちは、
I hope you enjoy us
お楽しみいただければと思います。
in artist mode.
アーティストですからね！
We're artists!
皆さん！アーティストっぽい格好してくださいね！
Everyone! Please dress like an artist!
かっこよく。
Looking cool.
アーティスト。
Artist.
かっこよく、かっこよく。
Cool, cool.
かっこよくね。
Stay cool.
爆速アーティストでございますから。
We are high-speed artists.
何か言いたい。
I want to say something.
形から入って。
Starting with appearances.
あ、いいいね、いいね。
Ah, nice, nice.
そうだね。
That's right.
オッケー牧場。
Okie-dokie.
えーアルバムを購入したよ、
For those who have already bought the album,
もう全曲聴いたよって方はより楽しんでもらえるように、
and listened to all the songs, to make it even more enjoyable,
まだアルバム買ってないよ、聴いてないよって方は
and for those who haven't bought or listened to it yet,
すぐにでも聴きたくなるような情報てんこ盛りでお送りしていきます。
we'll provide tons of information that will make you want to listen right away.
いたします。よろしくお願いします！
...we'll be doing that. Looking forward to it!
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to it!
イェーイ！
Yay!
アーティストモードで、皆さんも、なので紹介してくださいね。
Please introduce yourselves in artist mode too.
はい。続きアーティストモードで、真剣にアルバム紹介しちゃうけど、大丈夫？
Yes. Next, in artist mode, I'll seriously introduce the album. Is that okay?
何それ？ 何それ？ 何ボイスなんそれ？
What's that? What's that? What kind of voice is that?
いいね、いい。何ボイスなんそれ？
Nice, nice. What kind of voice is that?
ちょっとね、アーモンド... お。アーモンド？
A little bit of almond... oh. Almond?
違う。あ、ごめん、アーモンド何も関係ないっす。
No. Ah, sorry, almond has nothing to do with this.
なんか、皆のこう大物アーティスト感もどう出すのか、
I'm looking forward to seeing how you all bring out that "big artist" vibe,
それともいつものリグロスなのか、そういったところも見どころかなと思います。
or if it'll be the usual ReGLOSS. That's one of the highlights.
そして、配信の最後には、スペシャルミニライブもあります！ お楽しみに！
Also, at the end of the stream, there'll be a special mini-live! Look forward to it!
イェーイ！
Yay!
それでは！ アルバム大解剖スペシャル、スタートです！
Now then! The Album Deep Dive Special starts now!
イェーイ！
Yay!
え、まずはアルバムのね、収録曲をざっと見ていきましょうか。お待ちくださいね。
First, let's take a quick look at the tracks on the album. One moment, please.
お、よいしょ。おいしょ。
Oh, heave-ho. Heave-ho.
何それ？ 何？ 何？ 何だ何だ？
What is that? What? What? What's going on?
お、重い。持ってる。じゃじゃーん！
Oh, it's heavy. I'm holding it. Ta-da!
こんな感じになっております。01 瞬間ハートビート、02 シンメトリー、
This is what it looks like. 01 Shunkan Heartbeat, 02 Symmetry,
03 泡沫メイビー、04 フィーリンググラデーション、
03 Utakata Maybe, 04 Feeling Gradation,
05 bvdiz、06 SUPER DUPER、07 LAKI MODE、そして 08 瞬間ハートビートのリミックス！
05 bvdiz, 06 SUPER DUPER, 07 LAKI MODE, and 08 is the Shunkan Heartbeat remix!
リミックスを含め、全8曲でございますが、
Including the remix, there are eight tracks in total.
この8曲を見て、皆さん印象どうですか？ 奏。
Looking at these eight tracks, what are your impressions? Kanade.
え、実は奏、8曲目の瞬間ハートビートリミックスを、まだリグロスも聞いてなくて...
Actually, we in ReGLOSS hadn't even heard the 8th track, the Shunkan Heartbeat remix...
昨日の夜、配信された時に初めて聞いて、
I heard it for the first time when it was released last night,
あ、こう来たか、宇宙みたいな感じで凄いな！ と思ったのがまず1個あって、
and my first thought was, "Oh, so this is how it is! It feels like space, amazing!"
もう1個思ったのは、あの1曲目...
Another thing I thought was about tracks 1...
1曲目から4曲目が、ストーリーで繋がっていて、
Tracks 1 to 4 are connected by a story,
リグロスの1年を感じられるから、凄く素晴らしいなと思いました。
and you can really feel ReGLOSS's first year, so I thought it was wonderful.
いい感想や。いいね。そうね。青くんどうよ。
That's a great impression. Nice. True. How about you, Ao-kun?
いや、5から7曲目はとにかく楽しもうって感じがするし、
Well, tracks 5 to 7 definitely feel like they're all about having fun.
曲の雰囲気もガラッと変わるから、是非聞き応えもあるんで是非いっぱい聞いてください。
The atmosphere of the songs changes completely too, so please give them many listens!
ね、色んな曲があっていいよね。是非ね、皆さん聞いてください。
Yeah, it's great having such a variety of songs. Everyone, please listen to it.
アルバム出ました。よいしょ。ちょっとフリップも直しましてね。
The album is out now. Alright. Let me just fix the flip chart here.
おいしょ。ということでございまして。早速ね、瞬間ハートビートから順番にね、
There we go. And so... Right away, I'd like to do a deep dive, starting with "Shunkan Heartbeat"!
徹底解剖していきたいと思います！ イェーイ！
Now let's start the deep dive! Yay!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ステージ中央ご覧ください、皆さん。タブレットがあるんですが、
Look at the center of the stage, everyone. There's a tablet there.
この歌詞が好きだなとか、このトラックが好きだなーっていうの皆さんあると思います。
I'm sure you all have lyrics or tracks that you particularly like.
なので、今日せっかくなのでね、それをね、曲を流すことができる仕様にいたしました！ やった！
So, since we're here today, I've made it so we can play the songs! Yay!
イェーイ！ さあさあ、悪くないですよ。
Yay! Now, now, not bad.
アーティストの皆さんね、是非、あの「ここ流したいな」っていうのあれば、
You artists, if there's a part you'd like to play,
前に出てきてもらって、タブレットでね、流してください。よろしくお願いします。
please come forward and use the tablet to play it. Thank you.
畏まりました。どうしようかな、誰から行きます？
Understood. Let's see, who should go first?
じゃ、早速ね、瞬間ハートビートから色々ね、見ていこうかなと思うんですけども、
Well then, let's start looking into "Shunkan Heartbeat."
おいしょ。え、まずね、この瞬間ハートビート、聞いたことないよって人、まあいないかなと思うんですが、
Okay. First of all, I don't think there's anyone who hasn't heard "Shunkan Heartbeat," but...
一応ね、どんな曲なのか説明してもらおうかなと思います。リリカよろしく。
I'll have someone explain what kind of song it is. Ririka, please.
そうですね。ま、やはりこの「瞬間ハートビート」という曲は、リグロスの始まりの曲ですから、
Well... "Shunkan Heartbeat" is ReGLOSS's debut song, after all.
ま、私たち大切に歌わせてもらっておりますね。しかもかなり、こう、素敵な...
So, we sing it with great care. And it has a really lovely...
柔らかな感じの雰囲気の曲ですから、柔らかくはないか、なんて言うんだこういう時。
soft atmosphere to it. "Soft" might not be it. What do you call it?
まとめ、まとめていってください、リリカさん。ファビュラス、ファビュラス！
Please wrap it up, Ririka-san. Fabulous, fabulous!
そう、ファビュラスな感じの楽曲ですから、ま、あまりね、こう、力強くパンチアップ！
Yes, it's a fabulous track. So, I tried not to make it too powerful or punchy,
みたいな感じにならないように、肩の力を抜いて、モノローグかのように、
but rather relaxed my shoulders, and as if delivering a monologue,
美しく柔らかく、語りかけるように歌うことを心がけております。
aimed to sing it beautifully and softly, as if speaking to someone.
大物アーティストのイメージなのね、それがリリカさんのね。そうですね！
So that's your image of a big artist, Ririka-san. That's right!
ちょっとシャナリシャナリとした感じの大物アーティストでございますが、
A "big artist" with a bit of a graceful air.
なんか瞬間ハートビートのここ好きだなーみたいなところあれば是非聞きたいんですが、歌柱こと奏どうですか？
If there's a part of "Shunkan Heartbeat" you particularly like, I'd love to hear it. How about you, Kanade, our pillar of song?
あ、はい！ 奏は好きポイント、えー、瞬間ハートビートのサビのメロディがとても好きだなって思って。
Ah, yes! My favorite point is... I really love the melody of the chorus in "Shunkan Heartbeat."
あの、凄くうにょうにょしてるんですよ、メロディが。
The melody is really wiggly.
「こーころーうーばーわーれーたー」ってうにょうにょしてるところが、
The part where it goes "ko-ko-ro-u-ba-wa-re-ta" and wiggles around...
なんか凄くその曲をおしゃれに感じさせて、素晴らしいなと思いました。
It makes the song feel so stylish to me. I thought it was wonderful.
ポイント何なのかなって思って。
I was wondering what the points are.
まず一個好きだなと思ってるところがあるし...
First, there's one thing I like...
あと二個目ですごい良いなって思ったのは...
And the second thing I thought was really good...
あの1サビの時にはハーフで、ドゥン、ドゥドゥンっていうリズムで、ちょっとゆったり目で行くんですけど...
In the first chorus, it's half-time, with a 'dun, du-dun' rhythm, going a bit slow...
ラスサビでは、あの四つ打ちでドンドンドンドンって行くのが...
But in the last chorus, it has that four-on-the-floor beat, going 'dun-dun-dun-dun'...
最後にかけて盛り上げていこうみたいな感じが、すごく感じられて好きだなと思いました。
I really felt that 'let's build it up towards the end' vibe, and I loved it.
すごいビート感の違いが一曲の中に詰め込まれているということでございまして...
So the difference in beat feel is packed into one song...
えー、なんとね、今回、「徹底解剖スペシャル」ということで...
And now, for this 'Thorough Analysis Special'...
私たちの楽曲を作詞・作曲されているオートラさんに...
We've asked Ohtora-san, who wrote the lyrics and music for our songs...
いろいろ秘蔵話や楽曲のこだわり、なんと、聞いてきました！
About various behind-the-scenes stories and musical details!
おー！すごーい！なんてこっちゃ！
Oh! Amazing! No way!
色々聞いてきたんですが、まずは「瞬間ハートビート」というタイトル、どうしてこの曲名になったのかという理由でございます。
I asked many things, but first, the reason why the song was titled 'Shunkan Heartbeat.'
おおー！すごーい！
Ooh! Awesome!
1サビのハーフから最後のサビにかけて 脈数が早くなるトラックで、鼓動と似ていると思いました
I thought the track resembled a heartbeat, as the pulse increases from the half-time first chorus to the final chorus.
僕の中では心臓が羽を付けている絵が浮かび 瞬間ハートビートというタイトルにしました
In my mind, an image of a heart with wings appeared, so I titled it 'Shunkan Heartbeat.'
...とのことです！オートラさん、ありがとうございます！
...is what he said! Thank you, Ohtora-san!
オートラさんの喋り方なんだ、それ。
Is that how Ohtora-san talks?
ちょっとトラ代理やらせてもらってます。よろしくお願いします。
I'm acting as Tora's proxy. Nice to meet you.
どうですか皆さん、これ。「瞬間ハートビート」初めて聞いたよね。
What do you all think? We heard 'Shunkan Heartbeat' for the first time, right?
羽が生えた感じ。素敵。
Like it grew wings. Lovely.
確かにね、ふわっとするイメージもありつつ、走り出すイメージもありつつ...
True, it has that light, airy image, while also having a 'running start' image...
さっきのかなでが言ってた四つ打ちのところとかも、オートラさんのコメントと被ってるようなところがありまして...
The four-on-the-floor part Kanade mentioned earlier also overlaps with Ohtora-san's comments...
さすが音柱だなといった感じでございますが...
As expected of the Sound Hashira...
音柱！
Sound Hashira!
この後の楽曲紹介でも、オートラさんの秘蔵話や楽曲のこだわり、どんどん出てくるのでお楽しみに。
There'll be more of Ohtora-san's secrets and details in the following song intros, so stay tuned.
リリカ、「瞬間ハートビート」どう？好きなところとかある？
Lirika, how about 'Shunkan Heartbeat'? Any favorite parts?
えー、全部好きだけど...
Well, I like all of it...
やっぱり「瞬間ハートビート」のこの...
But especially this part of 'Shunkan Heartbeat'...
トクン。トクン。
Thump. Thump.
あれタイトルにもありますから、そう、心臓のドクドクのところ大好きです。
It's in the title too. Yes, I love the heart thumping part.
みんなにも踊ってほしい、一緒に歌いながら。
I want everyone to dance too, while singing along.
いや、わかる。そうね。
I totally get it. Right.
どう、番長は。せっかくだったら、もし流したいところとかあったら前に出てきて流せるよ。
How about you, Bancho? If there's a part you want to play, you can come forward and play it.
あとあとあと！
Wait, wait, wait!
おっ、どうぞ。どこだろう。中央センターステージへどうぞ。踊ってもいいよ。
Oh, go ahead. Where will it be? To the center stage, please. You can dance too.
えへ。聞かせてもらおうかな。
Hehe. Shall I let you hear it?
どうぞ。さあどこなのか。好きな箇所を、どうぞ！
Go ahead. Now, where is it? Your favorite part, please!
この衝動 止められはしない
This impulse cannot be stopped
この道を進むだけさ
Just moving forward on this path
なりふり構わず
Without a care in the world
Are you ready?
ここです！止められはしないからAre you readyのところまで。
Right here! From 'cannot be stopped' to 'Are you ready.'
なんかだんだんみんなの胸が高鳴っていって...
It feels like everyone's hearts are starting to race...
この衝動止められないで、もう行くしかないぜ、みたいな感じが...
That 'this impulse can't be stopped, we just gotta go' feeling...
なんかめっちゃ好きです。
I really like that.
確かに。いいこと言うね。最強。
True. Well said. The best.
お仕事完了！
Mission accomplished!
まだまだ1曲目ですから。まだまだいっぱいありますから。
This is just the first song. There are still many more.
リリカ、さっきのところ曲流せるらしいんだけど。嘘、流せないかも。
Ririka, apparently we can play that part... Oh, wait, maybe we can't.
他にもある？じゃあ、もう一個準備しておいたかっこいいことあるから、それ言ってもいい？
Any others? Well, I have another cool thing I prepared, can I say it?
「瞬間ハートビート」で気に入ってるところは、「キミと出会い カラフルに彩る ブランニューワールド」のところですね。
My favorite part in 'Shunkan Heartbeat' is 'Meeting you, colorful brand new world.'
何ちょっと笑ってるの？ブランニューワールド。
Why are you smiling a bit? Brand New World.
みんなメンバー、応援してくれるグロッサー、ひよこ隊ないとね...
Without the members, the Grossers who support us, and the Hiyoko-tai...
こう、みんなと出会って人生が変わった自分にとっても共感深いフレーズなのでね。
It's a phrase I really resonate with, since my life changed after meeting everyone.
なんかみんなと一緒にこれからもずっと一緒にいたいなみたいな気持ちがこもってて、とっても好きです。
It's filled with the feeling of wanting to be with everyone forever, so I love it.
心臓のトクントクンが好きです。アドリブ力ないからやめてほんと。
I like the heart thumping. Stop it, I'm bad at ad-libbing.
急に振られてビビったんだから。ごめんごめん。
I was surprised because you suddenly asked me. Sorry, sorry.
はい、以上、瞬間ハートビートの解説でございました。
Yes, that was the explanation for "Shunkan Heartbeat."
続きまして、
Next up,
アルバム収録2曲目、「シンメトリー」の解剖ね、していこうかなと思います！
we'll be dissecting the second track on the album, "Symmetry"!
イエーイ！オッケー！
Yay! Okay!
オッケー！
Okay!
えー、では「シンメトリー」どんな曲かというのを聞いていきたいと思います。シンメトリーを説明してください。
Well then, I'd like to hear what kind of song "Symmetry" is. Please explain "Symmetry."
じゃあ、奏、いこうかな！
Okay, Kanade, how about you!
うわー！
Whoa!
え、奏が「シンメトリー」を解釈してるときは、
Um, when I was interpreting "Symmetry,"
結構試練にぶち当たって、それを乗り越えていこうとする強い意志を感じる楽曲だなと思っています。
I felt it was a song with a strong will to face trials and try to overcome them.
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
歌詞と楽曲から強気な姿勢って感じがめちゃくちゃかっこいいなって思っています。
I think the assertive attitude from the lyrics and the music is really cool.
あと、この楽曲ですね、かっこいいフレーズがいっぱいあって、
Also, this song has a lot of cool phrases,
奏も、なんか歌っていて、「この曲かっこよく決めるぜ」っていう気持ちで歌うようにしてますね。
and even when I'm singing, I try to sing with the feeling of "I'm gonna nail this cool song."
うんうん。はい。
Uh-huh. Yes.
結構さ、瞬間ハートビートの次の曲だったから、比較してみてさ、
Since it was the next song after "Shunkan Heartbeat," comparing the two,
なんかやっぱりちょっと試練的な、ひと山、ふた山ある感覚とか、
it definitely feels like there's a trial or two to overcome,
なんか、やっぱ、あと曲の難易度的にも瞬間ハートビートよりちょっと難しくなってるのかな？みたいな。
and also in terms of difficulty, maybe it's a bit harder than "Shunkan Heartbeat"?
思った。
I thought so too.
あ、本当？
Oh, really?
そんな「シンメトリー」ですが、えー、ここでまた大虎さんからの秘蔵話、
That's "Symmetry" for you, but now, we have some insider info from Ohtoro-san,
シンメトリーに込めたテーマをお伺いしております！見てみましょう！こちらで、じゃじゃん！
the theme he put into "Symmetry"! Let's take a look! Here it is, ta-dah!
おおー！気になる！
Oh! I'm curious!
「まさしく試練をテーマに制作しました」奏、大正解！
"I specifically produced it with the theme of trials." Kanade, you were spot on!
やったー！素晴らしい！
Yay! Amazing!
「1曲目から曲調も変わり歌うのが難しかったですよね」はい、もうその通りでございます！
"The tone changed from the first song, making it difficult to sing, right?" Yes, exactly!
難しかったー！
It was hard!
落ち着いてニヤってしながら言ってほしいよね。「変わり、歌うの難しかったですよね、ニヤ」みたいな。
I want him to say it calmly with a smirk. "The tone changed, making it hard to sing, right? *smirk*"
どういうイメージなんだよ！
What kind of image do you have of him?!
ということでございまして、えー、あ、続きもメッセージありますね。
And so... oh, there's more to the message.
「でも、これぐらい歌ってくれよ！という僕からの試練として、この楽曲をご提供しました。」
"But I provided this song as a trial from me, saying 'Sing at least this well!'"
おおー！試練オンザ試練！
Oh! A trial on top of a trial!
ね、試練が重なってんな。重なってるな。
Yeah, the trials are stacking up. Stacking up.
いやでも、みんな頑張って歌ったからね、乗り越えられたんじゃないでしょうか。
But well, everyone worked hard to sing it, so I think we overcame it.
よかった。
That's good.
このね、「シンメトリー」っていう曲、みんなにもこう、どういうところがきー...好きっていうのを聞いていこうかなと、えー、思うんですけれども、
I'd like to ask everyone what they... like about this song "Symmetry,"
そうだな、じゃあお気に入り箇所、
let's see, favorite parts...
青くん、どっか好きなところある？
Ao-kun, do you have a part you like?
そうだね、やっぱり、「静かに灯す青い本能」ですね。
Right, it's gotta be "Blue instinct quietly lit."
おお、青くんのパートね！
Oh, Ao-kun's part!
いや、これ来たときに、もう歌詞先に見てもう、曲聴いて歌詞見たときに、「当て書き！？」ってなって。
When I got this and saw the lyrics first, then listened to the song and looked at the lyrics, I was like, "Was this written for me?!"
大虎さん、これ、僕でしょ！？って。
Ohtoro-san, this is about me, right?!
青だし青！火鳥青、青い本能。赤い炎より熱い本能なんですね。
Since it's Ao! Hiodoshi Ao, blue instinct. It's an instinct hotter than a red flame.
ふーん。青いほうが温度が高い。
Hmm. Blue is higher in temperature.
そっかそっか。いいなー。
I see, I see. Nice.
なんか、初めて歌詞見たときさ、青くんさ、「え、僕絶対ここがいい！」って言ってたよね。
When we first saw the lyrics, Ao-kun, you were saying, "Whoa, I definitely want this part!"
言った！言った！「これ僕！これ僕！これ僕！」って言って、で、ちゃんとそれになったから嬉しかった！
I did! I did! "This is me! This is me! This is me!" I said, and I was happy because it actually became my part!
無事にね。よかった。
Glad it worked out. That's good.
まさにね、ReGLOSSの青い本能でございますが、次、奏、聞いてみようかな。
Truly the blue instinct of ReGLOSS, but next, let's ask Kanade.
奏なんか、あのタブレットで流せるところあるらしいよ。
I heard Kanade has a part she can play on her tablet.
おおー！せっかくだったら流しちゃってくださいよ！
Oh! Since you're here, please play it!
奏のお気に入りポイントですが、まあ、まず、あの、キーがちょっと高くなって、あの、歌いやすくて気に入ってるんですよね。
Well, my favorite point is... first, the key gets a bit high, and it's easy for me to sing, so I like it.
おおー。
Oh.
っていうのは、まあ、冗談で。
Just kidding.
冗談かい！本気で受け取っちゃった。
You're kidding?! I took you seriously.
まあ本心で、あの、サビでメロディがガガーンって上がってくれたおかげでサビがめちゃくちゃ迫力が出るなと思っていて、そこ、なんかそのおかげと言いますか、
Well, in all seriousness, I think the chorus has a lot of impact because the melody really ramps up there, and thanks to that, or should I say...
自分のスイートスポットと言いますか、ちょうどかっこよく歌える音域でサビが来てくれて、気持ちよく歌えて好きだなと思っているので、ぜひ聴いてみてください。
it hits my sweet spot, where the chorus is in an octave where I can sing it coolly, and I really like how it feels to sing, so please give it a listen.
じわじわじわ... タブレットの方に。
Slowly... over to the tablet.
うわー！流します！
Whoa! I'm playing it!
どうぞ！どのパートなんだろう。こちら！
Go ahead! I wonder which part it is. This one!
あ、サビだ！一番高いところ。
Oh, it's the chorus! The highest part.
おおー。確かに、ここ結構高いもんね！
Oh. Indeed, this part is quite high!
ねー！ガツンと来てくれるから気持ちいいんだよね。
Right! It hits hard, so it feels great.
ちょっと映像もリンクしてるよ、後ろの。本当だ！たまたま。
The visuals are linked too, in the back. You're right! By coincidence.
ここのね、ダンスも素敵なんですよね、番長。
The dance here is wonderful too, Bancho.
え、ありが...ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank... thank you.
え、あ、誰が、誰が振付作ったんだっけ？あれ？
Wait, who, who choreographed this again? Hmm?
あれ？誰だ？誰だ？
Wait? Who was it? Who was it?
あ、はじめ...！
Ah, Hajime...!
イエーイ！番長！さすが！
Yay! Bancho! As expected!
あやちゃ。ありがとうございます。これ、サビだよね。サビの振付作ったのは、はじめでございます。
Thank you. This is the chorus, right. It was Hajime who choreographed the chorus.
はい、ということでございまして。
Yes, and so...
ぜひ、あの3Dライブのアーカイブもこちらのチャンネルで見れますので、ぜひこの配信が終わったあと見てみてください。
Please check out the 3D live archive as well, it's available on this channel, so please take a look after this stream ends.
では、えー、そんなシンメトリーの解説でございました。
Well, that was the explanation for "Symmetry."
続きまして、えー、3曲目いきましょうか。
Moving on, let's go to the third track.
3曲目、えー、ガラッと雰囲気変わります。
The third track... the atmosphere changes completely.
『泡沫メイビー』の徹底解剖でございます。
It's time for a thorough dissection of "Utakata Maybe."
おおー！
Ohhh!
まずね、この『泡沫メイビー』という曲の説明を...
First, for the explanation of this song, "Utakata Maybe"...
じゃあ、青くん！あれ？
Well then, Ao-kun! Huh?
はい！
Yes!
そうですね。
That's right.
やはり『泡沫メイビー』。『泡沫』で『メイビー』なわけなんですけれども。
After all, it's "Utakata Maybe." It's "Utakata" (bubble) and "Maybe."
はい。
Yes.
そんな中で、僕がやっぱり言いたいのは...
In that context, what I really want to say is...
僕の解釈ではあるんですが。
This is just my interpretation.
まだまだ僕たちは発展途上。
We are still a work in progress.
ふわふわと泡沫のように自分たちの立ち位置が不安定な状態。
Our position is unstable, floating like bubbles.
でも前だけを見つめていこうと心の中で小さく決意をする。
But we make a quiet resolution in our hearts to keep looking forward.
そんな解釈です。
That's my interpretation.
かっこいいー！
So cool!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ま、やっぱり僕、ちょっとね、解釈とか、あの国語得意なんで、こういうの考えるの好きです。
Well, I'm good at interpretation and Japanese, so I like thinking about these things.
素晴らしい。いい、いい。
Wonderful. Good, good.
え、なに？今おでこからなんか出してた？
Wait, what? Were you letting something out of your forehead just now?
あの、泡沫を...あ、泡沫を...
Um, the bubbles... ah, the bubbles...
あ、泡沫、なるほど。そっから出るんだ。
Ah, bubbles, I see. They come out of there.
怖い、出てる。
Scary, it's coming out.
泡沫がそっから...
Bubbles from there...
なんかね、この曲、なんか、まあいっぱい今回アルバム曲入ってるじゃないですか。
You know, this song... well, there are many songs in the album this time.
そん中で、なんかどれが一番、強いて言うならね、どれが一番好き？
Among them, if I were forced to pick, which one do I like best?
って言われた時に、らでん絶対『泡沫メイビー』って答えるの。
If asked that, I'd definitely say "Utakata Maybe."
おおー！
Ohhh!
そんぐらい結構好きで。やっぱこう、3曲目で結構サウンドの感じがガラッと変わるじゃない？
I like it that much. After all, the sound changes completely at the third track, right?
そうだね。
True.
すごいね、なんかこう、潤った滑走路みたいなイメージがあって。
It's amazing, it has this image of a lush runway.
なんかそういうので、その雰囲気が違うっていうのもあり、ちょっとしっとり聴かせるっていうのもあり...
Because of that, the atmosphere is different, and it's a bit more mellow...
で、3Dライブのあれもあってね、スタンドマイクでのパフォーマンスだったじゃない。唯一、その『泡沫メイビー』。
And with the 3D live, it was a performance with stand mics. The only one, "Utakata Maybe."
そうね。
That's right.
そこもね、なんかちょっと、思い出深いというか。すごーい、アーティストみたい、と思って歌ってましたけど。
That part is also memorable. I felt like a real artist while singing it.
確かに。
True.
えー、ここで、Ohtoraさんの秘蔵話、『泡沫メイビー』バージョンもありますよ。こちらデン！デデン！
Now, we have a secret story from Ohtora-san, for the "Utakata Maybe" version. Here it is!
実家のような安心感、いつでもここに帰ってきていいよ というのを表現したくバラードにしました
I made it a ballad to express a sense of security like being at home, saying 'you can come back here anytime'.
辛いことがあったらこの曲を聴きに帰ってきてください きっとこの曲がそっと背中を押してくれます
If something painful happens, please come back to listen to this song. I'm sure this song will gently give you a push.
「実家のような安心感。いつでもここに帰ってきていいよ」というのを表現したくバラードにしました。
"I made it a ballad to express a sense of security like being at home, saying 'you can come back here anytime'."
確かに。
Certainly.
まさにそうだよね。なんかいつでも垂れ流せるような曲調だな、って。
That's exactly right. It's the kind of tune you can just have playing in the background anytime.
落ち着くよね、聴いてるとね。
It's calming when you listen to it.
「辛いことがあったらこの曲を聴きに帰ってきてください。きっとこの曲がそっと背中を押してくれます」とのことです。
"If something painful happens, please come back to listen to this song. I'm sure this song will gently give you a push."
ありがとうございます！そっと！
Thank you very much! Gently!
いやぁ、確かに実家のような安心感...まあ安心感は結構『泡沫メイビー』、このアルバムの中でもピカイチであるのかな、と。
Yeah, it really does have that homey security... I think "Utakata Maybe" has the best sense of security in this album.
みんなの、ね、お気に入り箇所、ここ好き！っていうのもね、聞いていければな、と思います。
I'd like to hear everyone's favorite parts, like "I love this part!"
じゃあどうしようかな、はじめ、と、あげまちを。
Well then, how about Hajime and Agemachi (Ririka)?
お！じゃあ流しちゃおうか。
Oh! Shall we play it then?
どうぞどうぞ、流しちゃってよ。一丁！
Go ahead, play it. Here we go!
いいよー。あ、ここ！
Alright. Ah, here!
どこだ？これ。歌ってる後ろで流れてるやつじゃない？
Where is this? Isn't this the part playing behind the singing?
あ、じゃ、うん、だよう、って...ここだね。
Ah, well, yes, "...dayou" and then... it's here.
あの後ろで流れてる音だけを抽出してもらった時の...
When I had just the background sound extracted...
ええー！？
Ehhh!?
マニアックすぎる。マニアックだけど。番長がキョトンとしてる。
That's way too niche. Niche, but... Hajime looks blank.
流しちゃった、みたいな感じだけど。
She looks like, "Oops, it played."
でも、番長どっちも好きな。あ、ここも超良いっしょ。
But I like both. Ah, this part is super good too, right?
あ、はじめが言いたかったのは、なんかあの、始まりとか、ポン、ポチュ、ポチュ、ポチュ、ってなんか...
Ah, what I wanted to say was, like the beginning, the "pon, pochu, pochu, pochu" sound...
水滴が広がる音あるじゃないですか。なんかそういうのがすごい好きだな、って思って。
You know that sound of water droplets spreading? I really liked that.
ああー！いいよー！
Ahhh! That's good!
でも今のも良かった。
But the one just now was good too.
今のも良かった。お疲れ様。
The one just now was good too. Good job.
可愛い音だよね。なんか結構音周りとかね。
It's a cute sound. The overall sound design is nice.
最初に『泡沫メイビー』聞いた時、「あ、この音好き！」みたいな感じでみんなで話してたりとかもありましたけれども。
When we first heard "Utakata Maybe", we were all talking like, "Ah, I love this sound!"
他にもお気に入り箇所聞いていこうかな。じゃあ青くんは？
Let's hear other favorite parts. How about you, Ao-kun?
そうですね。僕も流しちゃおうかな。あ、アーティスト火威青入ります。
Well. I'll play mine too. Ah, artist Hiodoshi Ao mode: on.
おおー！
Ohhh!
どこだろう。どれだ？うん、これか？ここ。流してみて、違ったら違う時。
Where is it? Which one? Um, this one? Here. Play it, and if it's wrong, it's wrong.
ミュージックスタート！
Music start!
もう後ろを振り返らないで と呟いたんだ
"Don't look back anymore," I whispered.
青くんの最後のところだ。
It's Ao-kun's last part.
ここ。なんかもう、本当にそのまま「後ろを振り返らないで」...
Here. Like, literally, "don't look back"...
歌詞がすごい良かった...
The lyrics were really good...
割とこう、なんだろう、自分でも...
It's like, how should I put it, even for me...
この活動をしていくにあたって...
...in terms of carrying out these activities...
デビューして、こういう活動をしていくにあたって...
...after debuting and doing these activities...
自分でもたまに同じようなことを自分に言い聞かせたことがあったんですよね。
I've occasionally told myself similar things.
おおー。
Ohhh.
そういう過去があった上で、この歌が届いた時に...
Having that past, when this song reached me...
あ、めちゃめちゃいい曲だなって...
I thought, "Ah, what a great song."
すごく深く思った上に、ここ歌ってんの俺！サンキュー！って...
On top of feeling that deeply, I thought, "I'm the one singing this! Thank you!"
気分がいいです。帰ります！
I feel great. I'm going home!
アーティストどこ行った？
Where did the artist go?
ねえ、芸人になって帰ってきた。
Hey, he came back as a comedian.
僕はキャラを作らない。
I don't build a character.
僕は常にアーティスト。
I'm always an artist.
あ、いいですね。そりゃそうかもね。私達一応アーティストグループでございますから。
Oh, nice. That might be true. We are an artist group, after all.
一応って言わないで！
Don't say "after all"!
すみません。アーティストグループでございます。
Sorry. We are an artist group.
これさ、ちょっとみんなに聞きたいんだけど...
You know, I want to ask everyone something...
レコーディングの時、「泡沫メイビー」の時、結構さ...
During the recording of "Utakata Maybe", it was quite...
今までの「瞬間ハートビート」「シンメトリー」と違う歌い方でディレクションされたんだけど...
...directed with a different singing style from "Shunkan Heartbeat" or "Symmetry".
された！された！
We were! We were!
された？みんななんて言われてた？その時。
You were? What were you all told? At that time.
なんか、ちょっと背伸びした大人みたいな感じで歌ってくださいって言われた記憶がある。
I remember being told to sing like a slightly grown-up person trying to act mature.
おなじおなじー！
Same here!
言われてないかも。僕は。
I might not have been told that.
僕は常にわりと褒め伸びだから。
I'm always the type who grows through praise.
「青くん青くんいいよ！そのままそのまま！いいよいいよかっこいいかっこいい！オッケーそのまま行こう！」って言われてる。
"Ao-kun, Ao-kun, that's good! Just like that! Good, good, cool, cool! OK, let's go with that!"
ちょっと大人っぽく、なんか力を抜いて歌ってくださいって言われた。
I was told to sing a bit more maturely, with less power.
なるほど。いいですね。リリは何も言われてないの？その時。
I see. That's nice. Riri, weren't you told anything? At that time.
えぇーっ！？もう覚えてない！
What!? I don't remember anymore!
でも、いつも素敵なディレクションしてくれてて、多分なんか...
But they always give wonderful direction, so probably...
ちょっと色っぽく、優しく、こう大人っぽく歌ってみて、みたいな感じでは確かにあったかもしれない。
...it was certainly something like "try singing a bit sexier, gentler, and more maturely."
なるほど。おでんはどうだったの？
I see. How about you, Oden?
らではね、この時、なんかもお、ずーっと...
For me, at that time, like, the whole time...
「らでんさん、大丈夫です。らでんさん、力抜きましょう」
"Raden-san, it's okay. Raden-san, let's relax."
って歌うじゃん。「うん、らでんさん、力を抜きましょう」
I'd sing, and they'd go, "Yes, Raden-san, let's relax."
緊張してたのかな？
Were you nervous?
もうすごい力入ってたんで、「1回、大丈夫なんで、1回力抜きましょう」って、ずーっと多分この状態だった。
I was so tense, so they were like, "Once more, it's okay, let's relax for a bit," and I was probably like this the whole time.
ちょっと誇張しすぎだと言われて...まぁそんな感じだったのね。結構らでの中でも新しい歌い方を身に付けたというか。
I was told I was exaggerating a bit... but it was like that. I feel like I acquired a new way of singing.
すごいね、思い出深い曲でございます。えー、「泡沫メイビー」の解剖でした。ありがとうございました！
It's a very memorable song. So, that was the breakdown of "Utakata Maybe". Thank you very much!
はい、では次行きましょう。4曲目でございますね。えー、4曲目の「フィーリングラデーション」の徹底解剖をしていきます。
All right, let's move on. It's the 4th song. We'll be doing a thorough breakdown of the 4th song, "Feeling Gradation".
「フィーリングラデーション」、どんな曲でしょうか。説明をお願いします。じゃあ、番長！
"Feeling Gradation", what kind of song is it? Please explain. Go ahead, Bancho!
はい！
Yes!
えー、まぁなんか、ReGLOSSデビューして1年ぐらい経ったけど...
Well, about a year has passed since ReGLOSS debuted...
ここから改めて再スタートするぞ、新しくまた始まりの時が来たんだ！
...and we're going to restart from here; a new beginning has come!
スタートラインに改めて立った、ここからが俺達野郎！みたいな解釈で歌っております。
We've stood at the starting line again, and from here on, it's our turn! That's the interpretation I sang with.
素晴らしい！さすがです、はじめ社長。
Wonderful! As expected of Hajime-shacho.
さすがアーティストはじめ。
As expected of the artist, Hajime.
まぁ、やはり、あの...我が言うことに間違いはない！
Well, as expected... there is no mistake in what I say!
1人称「我」！？魔王！？魔王みたいになるんだね。
First person "wa" (I)!? Like a Demon King!? You become like a Demon King.
この「フィーリングラデーション」はさ、なんか、まぁ4曲目でMVがさ、うちら史上初のアニメーションだったじゃない？
"Feeling Gradation", you know, it's the 4th song, and the MV was our first ever animation, right?
これ見た時さ、「あー、ReGLOSSで良かった」ってなったんだよ、すごく。
When I saw this, I thought, "Ah, I'm glad I'm in ReGLOSS." It was really like that.
わかる！
I understand!
ちょっと泣きそうになったもんね、初めて見た時。
I almost cried when I saw it for the first time.
泣きました。
I cried.
じゃあ、らでも泣いたことにします。泣きました。
Then, I'll count it as I cried too. I cried.
みんな泣きました！
Everyone cried!
やっぱ、穴という穴からめっちゃ水出たわ。
Yeah, water came out of every hole.
ちょっと待って！アーティスト！
Wait a minute! Artist!
アーティスト！帰ってきて！一条さん！
Artist! Come back! Ichijou-san!
ってことでね、みんなの好きなところを聞いていこうかなと思うんですけれども...
So, I want to ask everyone what their favorite parts are...
リリカ、どこが好きとかある？流せるよ。
Ririka, do you have a part you like? We can play it.
実はね、リリカ、「フィーリングラデーション」が一番お気に入りの曲で。大好きなんですけど。
Actually, "Feeling Gradation" is my most favorite song. I love it.
せっかくだから流させてもらおうかな！
Since I have the chance, I'll play it!
リリカはね、やっぱり...
For me, it's definitely...
これかな！いける？ピ。
Maybe this! Can we do it? Press.
あー、サビだね！そう、サビのところが一番好き！
Ah, it's the chorus! Yeah, I like the chorus the best!
ここのね、ダンスもいいんで。みんな覚えたダンス。
The dance here is also good. The dance everyone learned.
いいメロディだよね。
It's a nice melody.
このやっぱり「リスタートライン」っていうのが1個キーワードなんだろうね、「フィーリングラデーション」。
I guess "restart line" is a key word for "Feeling Gradation".
そうだね！もう一回リスタート！
That's right! Restarting once more!
すみません。
Excuse me.
え、どうしたの？
Eh, what's wrong?
番長のコメントが視界に入ってきて...
Bancho's comment came into view...
収録曲 大解剖SP / ♪泡沫メイビー解説
Songs Breakdown SP / ♪Utakata Maybe Commentary
#ReGLOSSアルバム発売
#ReGLOSSAlbumRelease
雲と雲の切れ間から
Between the clouds
失った過去も
The lost past too
♪フィーリングラデーション解説
♪Feeling Gradation Commentary
飛び出せ！
Fly out!
ときめいて今
Sparkle now
番長の... フィーリングラデーションどこが一番好きですか？
Captain... which part of 'Feeling Gradation' do you like best?
旅が好きです。
I like the journey.
これしか書いてなくて... ごめんなさい。
I only wrote that much... I'm sorry.
いいじゃん！ 他みんな長めなのに...
It's fine! Everyone else wrote quite a bit, but...
でも結局旅が好きってことでしょ。番長は。
But in the end, you just really like 'the journey,' right?
ごめんごめん、何も悪くないんだけど...
Sorry, sorry, it's not bad at all...
今視界に入ってびっくりしちゃった。吹き出しちゃいました。
But seeing it just now surprised me. I couldn't help laughing.
この配信するにあたって、みんなに事前アンケートをとってるんですよね。
For this stream, we took a survey from everyone beforehand.
「どこが好きですか？」みたいなアンケートをとってて...
We asked things like, "Which part do you like?"
番長ちょいちょい一言しか書いてない。
And Captain frequently wrote just a single word.
ちょっと面白い。
It's pretty funny.
語彙力がないね。
Not much vocabulary there.
違います！
That's not it!
番長は背中で語るから。
Captain speaks with her back.
言葉で語ってよ。背中で語るな。
Speak with words! Don't speak with your back.
かっこいい！ 番長！ かっこいい！
So cool! Captain! So cool!
次は青君に振っちゃおうかな。好きなところある？
Next, let's ask Ao-kun. Do you have a favorite part?
音源流せるよ。流しちゃおうか、じゃあ。
I can play the track. Shall we play it, then?
おっ、流しちゃおうかな、じゃあ。
Oh, let's play it, then.
おっ、どこだろう？
Oh, which part should it be?
僕は、サビみんな言ってるから、サビじゃないところ流そうかな。
Everyone's mentioning the chorus, so I'll play a different part.
おおー！ どこかな？
Ooh! Where is it?
どこかな、どこかな... どこだ？ どこだ...
Where is it... let's see... where?
下の段かな？ 下の青いのかな？
The bottom row? The blue one at the bottom?
あ、これか。
Ah, this one.
目まぐるしく 昔々
Dizzyingly, long ago
おおー！ かっこいい！
Ooh! So cool!
ここから先は まだ誰も知らない
From here on, nobody knows yet
ここね、いいよね。
This part is great, isn't it?
傍観してるだけじゃ 味気ない
Just watching is boring
リアルタイムで 通じ合って
Connecting in real-time
ここ好きですね。
I love this part.
また自分が歌ってるところですいませんけど。
Sorry for picking a part where I sing again.
いやいやいや。ここね、最後のさ...
No, no, no. This part, at the end...
「リアルタイムで通じ合って」の、高い声、誰なのこれ？
That high voice in "Connecting in real-time," who is it?
高い声？
High voice?
青君の「リアルタイムで通じ合って」の上に、もう一人いるじゃん。
There's another voice above yours during that line, right?
「リアルタイムでー」って言ってる人。
The person singing "Real-time..." in a high pitch.
覚えてないかも。
I might not remember.
一回流す？
Should we play it again?
でもまあ、アンケート取りましょうか。
Well, let's ask the audience in a poll.
そうね。そうね。
Right. Right.
でも大体の2曲目以降のハモリ、大体僕やってるから。
But I generally do the harmonies from the second track onwards.
ずっといるし、下に。
I'm always there, underneath.
アルバムで聴くとわかる。
You can tell if you listen to the album.
ありがたい。でもいいところですよね。
Thank you. It really is a great part.
全体曲だけど、こうやって2人ずつ歌ったり、3人ずつ歌ったりみたいな...
It's a group song, but it has sections with pairs or trios singing...
そういうコーナーが結構色々ある曲だと思ってて。
I feel like this song has many such segments.
ここね、奏ちゃんと2人で歌ってるんで。
In this part, I'm singing with Kanade-chan.
フリあるよね。チュ、チュ、チュ、セヨっていうのが。
There's a move, right? The "Chu, chu, chu, seyo" part.
ちなみにね、大虎さんのメモのほうなんですけども...
By the way, regarding Ohtora-san's memo...
青君について一個もらってて。
There was a note specifically about Ao-kun.
青君は、高音も出るし、音域の幅を感じるらしい。
Apparently, Ao-kun can hit high notes and has a wide vocal range.
青君が思う以上に、音域の幅が広いと。
His range is supposedly wider than he even realizes.
やったー！ 嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
3Dライブのときも、体幹がしっかりしてる人の歌い方で...
During the 3D live, his singing style showed a solid core...
歌声が安定してたっていう、相当な努力量を積んでると感じたって大虎さんからいただいております。
His voice was stable, and Ohtora-san felt a massive amount of effort was put in.
帰ります！
I'm going home! (Embarrassed)
ちょっと恥ずかしくなっちゃった。番長、照れちゃった。
He got a bit shy. Captain's blushing.
嬉しい。ま、ちょっとね。
I'm happy. Well, a little.
ありがとうございました。続きまして5曲目でございますね。
Thank you very much. Moving on to the 5th track.
「buddies」の徹底解剖していきましょう。
Let's do a deep dive into "buddies."
「buddies」でございます。
It's "buddies."
ここは私から紹介させていただきます。
I'll be introducing this one.
「buddies」、やっぱタイトルにもあります通り、「仲間」だね。
"buddies," as the title suggests, is about "companions."
仲間と一緒にこうワチャワチャしながら頑張っていくぜ。
It's about having fun and working hard together with friends.
たまにはみんなで遊ぼうぜ、飲みに行こうぜ、みたいなそんな曲でございます。
It's a song about hanging out and going for drinks together.
「buddies」でございますね。
That's "buddies."
みんなね、こう「ワー！」ってやる感じの曲、みんなすごい好きだなって思うんだけど。
It's a high-energy song that everyone seems to really enjoy.
どう、リリ？
What do you think, Riri?
えー、いやそうだね。やっぱりなんか「buddies」ってそのタイトルの通り...
Yeah, exactly. "buddies," just like the title implies...
仲間みたいなところをすごい強く意識する曲かなと思ってて。
I think it's a song that strongly emphasizes companionship.
徐々にみんなお互いのことがより分かり合えてきて。
We've gradually come to understand each other better.
かつ、そういう良き仲間がずっとそばにいるんだよなーっていうのを...
And keeping the fact that such good friends are always by our side...
頭の中に、心の中に留めながら、なんか気配を感じながら歌ってるなって思います。
In our minds and hearts, feeling their presence while singing.
いいねえ。
That's lovely.
今回もですね、大虎さんの秘蔵話いただいております。
Once again, we have a special story from Ohtora-san.
こちらも曲に込めたテーマでいただいております。こちらドン。
He shared the theme he put into the song. Here it is.
とにかく楽しいをテーマに / メンバー/お客さんと一緒に歌える曲になっているかと
Theme is "just have fun." A song members and fans can sing together.
「とにかく楽しい」をテーマに。メンバーやお客さんと一緒に歌える曲になっているかと。
The theme is "just having fun." It's meant to be a song members and fans can sing together.
あと、各メンバーの歌い分けは拘って作りました！
Also, I put a lot of care into the distribution of singing parts for each member!
あと...
Also...
各メンバーの歌い分けは拘って作りました、とのことです。
He says he was very particular about the line distribution for each member.
歌い分けか。歌い分け、歌い分け...
Line distribution, huh? Line distribution...
歌い分け、歌い分け結構ね...
The line distribution is quite varied...
バラバラで。ちゃんと最初のね、ごちゃごちゃになってるよね。
It's all over the place. The beginning is especially mixed up.
奏、好きなところあれば流せるよ、今。
Kanade, if you have a favorite part, I can play it now.
今出たところでもいいし、別のところでもいいし。
Either the part we just saw or a different one.
やあ！
Hey!
じゃじゃっと、えっと、奏の「Buddyz」のお気に入りポイントはこちら。
Tada! Um, here is my favorite point of "Buddyz."
流します！どうぞ！
I'll play it! Here you go!
あ、最初だね！
Oh, it's the beginning!
この振り奏ちゃんしかやってないけどね。
Only Kanade-chan is doing this move, though.
そうなの！ここ好き、可愛いの。
That's right! I like this part; it's cute.
この奏ダンス。
This Kanade dance.
ん、ここ良いよね！
Yeah, this part is great!
良いね！
It is!
このね、「Okidoki Easy Breezy」って繰り返されるパートがね、
This repeating part, "Okidoki Easy Breezy,"
すごくキャッチーで耳に残るなって思ってて。
is so catchy and stays in my head.
みんなね踊りたくなるような、すごい楽しいフレーズだなと思いました。
I thought it was a really fun phrase that makes everyone want to dance!
お気に入り。
My favorite.
良いよね。
It's nice.
僕ちなみに一番好きな曲これ。
By the way, this is my favorite song.
おー！
Oh!
そうなの？「Buddyz」？
Really? "Buddyz"?
はい。
Yes.
好きなところとかある？「ここが良い」みたいな。
Is there something specific you like? Like, "this part is great."
なんか一発目聴いた時実は正直、
To be honest, when I first heard it,
一番苦手な曲でした。歌えないっていう意味で。
it was the song I struggled with most. In the sense that I couldn't sing it.
ええー！
Whaaaat!
およ？およ？音が？
Oh? Oh? The notes?
高くて、歌えないかもっていうのと、あとその時、
They were high, so I thought I might not be able to sing it. Also, at the time,
個人的になんだけど、あんまりReGLOSSに自分って必要なのかな？
it's just a personal thing, but I was wondering if I was really needed in ReGLOSS.
って思ってた時期にこの曲が来たの。
This song came to me during that period.
ええ！そうだったの？
Whoa! Really?
けど、その後にロケがあって、ロケでみんなと、
But after that, we had a location shoot, and during that shoot,
涙ながらに手紙を読み合った後に、もう一度家に帰って聴いてみたの。
after we read letters to each other through tears, I went home and listened to it again.
一番好きになっちゃった。
And it became my absolute favorite.
わあー！
Aww!
良いこと言う！
That's so sweet!
リリカ！
Ririka!
火威青！
Hiyodoshi Ao!
待って、青でしょそこは！
Wait, it's supposed to be Ao there!
なんでや！
Why though!
そうね、1周年のロケだね。みんなで行きまして、
Right, the 1st anniversary shoot. We all went,
その時に、まああの、涙あり笑いありの手紙のね、やり取りがあったんですけれども。
and at that time, we had that tearful and joyful exchange of letters.
やっぱり仲間をテーマにやってるからこそ、こう、自分たちの間で実感が湧いた時にさらにね、
Since the theme is about comrades, once we truly felt that bond,
ひとつふたつじんわり来るっていう曲にね、なっております。
the song started to resonate with us even more deeply.
「Buddyz」、ぜひね皆様も聴いてください！
Please everyone, do give "Buddyz" a listen!
はい！
Yes!
どう？リリカはどう？
How about you? What about you, Ririka?
え、リリカは、
Um, for me,
「運命共同体でうっしっししてゆく喜怒哀楽」のところが、
the part "Destiny bound together, laughing through ups and downs,"
なんか、ついね口ずさんじゃうぐらいなんか好きだし、もうこの歌詞のフレーズがね、
I love it so much I find myself humming it. This lyrical phrase,
まさにReGLOSSっていう感じがしてめちゃめちゃ好きです！
it feels exactly like ReGLOSS, so I really love it!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
僕も同じこと書いた！
I wrote the same thing!
リリカ！
Ririka!
火威青！
Hiyodoshi Ao!
バカスーいだなあ！
What a silly goose!
やっぱり青じゃないんですね。どうして？
So it's still not Ao. Why?
ということで、「Buddyz」の解説でございました！
And that concludes the explanation of "Buddyz"!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ではではですね、ここからユニット曲に移ろうかなと思います。
Well then, let's move on to the unit songs.
6曲目は、わたくし儒烏風亭らでんとリリカと青君3人の、
The 6th track is by Juufuutei Raden, Ririka, and Ao-kun.
「SUPER DUPER」でございます！
It's "SUPER DUPER"!
SUPER DUPER!
こちらも説明してもらおうかなと思うんですけれども。
I'd like to have an explanation for this one too.
どんな曲？青君、リリカ、どっちでも良いよ。青リリの二人は。
What kind of song is it? Ao-kun, Ririka, either is fine. Ao-Riri duo.
良い曲だよね。
It's a great song.
最高だよね。
It's the best.
みんなも盛り上がる。
Everyone gets hyped.
大好きなメンバーと。
With my favorite members.
かっこいいし。
It's cool.
大好きな応援してくれるみんなとあち、一緒に...
Together with all the fans who support us...
ああ、戻ってきた！たしか。
Oh, it came back! I think.
ね、楽しい時間を共有できてるようなね、感じのする曲だから大好きです！
Right, I love it because it feels like we're sharing a fun time together!
イェーイ！って感じでね、盛り上がる曲なのもすごい良いなと思います。
It's great that it's an upbeat song that goes "Yeah!"
そうね。なんか歌う時にさ、気をつけてるところとかどう青君とかは？
Right. Ao-kun, what are some things you paid attention to while singing?
そうだね。なんか僕結構自分のパートは、なんかこの曲で一番しっとりしてるところが全部僕なんですよ。
Well, for my parts, I'm responsible for all the mellow sections in this song.
うんうん。
Mm-hmm.
そう自分が歌ってるところは...
So, where I'm singing...
お、やめろ！おい！
Hey, stop it! Hey!
ガキンちょ！
Brat!
はい、あの、しっとりしてるけど、でも曲は明るいから。
Yes, so, it's mellow, but the song itself is bright.
で、声も低いからちょっと音が暗くならないように...
And since my voice is low, I tried not to let the sound get too dark...
おいおいおい...
Hey, hey, hey...
あのね、遊ばないでください。
Listen, please stop playing around.
明るいサウンドになるように努力しながらかつ、でもセクシーに行きたいなと思ってます。
I'm trying to make the sound bright while also aiming for a sexy feel.
ええ。
Yeah.
そうですね。ちょこちょこちょこちょこなんかね、あれでございましたけれども。
Right. There was a bit of distraction there, but anyway.
ここでOHTORAさんの秘蔵話いただいております。
We've received a special story from Ohtora-san.
こちらは3人へメッセージですかね？お願いします、こちらです！
Is this a message for the three of you? Here it is!
デレン！
Ta-da!
曲のテーマは爆発力！
The theme of the song is explosive power!
爆発！
Explosion!
この3人が揃うと底知れぬ爆発力がある印象です。
I get the impression that when these three come together, there's an unfathomable explosive power.
爆発力。
Explosive power.
パラパラ感がある曲に新しいビートサウンドを取り入れ、
I incorporated a new beat sound into a song with a "parapara" feel,
BPMも早い！7曲の中で歌うのが一番難しいと思います。
and the BPM is fast too! I think it's the most difficult to sing among the seven tracks.
おー！
Oh!
カレー！
Curry!
これさ、この曲奏に来なくてよかった！
You know, I'm glad this song didn't come to me!
なんで？なんで？
Why? Why?
難しいし、なんか常にこうやって振りも入ってるから。
Because it's hard, and it has dance moves like this throughout.
良かった
Glad to hear that.
えー
Eh?
えー！LAKI MODEも難しいけどな
Eh! LAKI MODE is also difficult, though.
うん、LAKI MODEもね
Yeah, LAKI MODE too.
うちめっちゃ大好きだから、ずっと言ってるもんね
I really love it, I've been saying it for a long time.
歌ってたよね、歌枠で
You sang it, right? In a singing stream.
Yeah yeah yeah, Woah woah woah...
LAKI MODEもちゃんかちしたかったし
I wanted to nail LAKI MODE too.
大好き、ここ
I love this part.
どう？自分が歌うってなって、歌枠で一回歌ってたじゃん
How was it? When you decided to sing it,
you sang it once in a singing stream.
うん
Yeah.
難しかった？
Was it difficult?
むっちゃ難しかった！めっちゃ練習すごいした
It was really difficult! I practiced so much.
難しいよね
It's difficult, isn't it?
なんかね、ラップの部分みたいな早口のところもあるもんね
Like, there are fast-paced parts like rap sections.
ね、あるある
Yeah, there are.
そんなね、早口なところで、この3人がね
In such fast-paced parts, these three...
ここのフレーズ、この歌詞好きって言ったところが、
なんと3人一致していたんですよね
...where they said they like this phrase or these lyrics,
surprisingly, all three of them agreed.
なに？
What is it?
ぜひね、流そうかなと思います。リリカさん、お願いしていいですか？
I'd like to play it. Ririka-san, could you please?
はい
Okay.
なかななね、3人全部一緒になることないんだけど
It's quite rare for all three to match.
そうだね
That's true.
バチッとね
Perfectly.
流しますよ
I'll play it.
お願いします
Please do.
運命...
Fate...
おー、間違えた！
Oh, I made a mistake!
奏の声が！すいません、間違えました。ぽち
Kanade's voice! Sorry, I made a mistake. Click.
今のはBUDDY'Sですね
That was BUDDY'S.
あ、ここですね
Ah, it's here.
(SUPER DUPER Snippet)
ちょっとお詫びのダンスで
A dance to apologize...
何してるの？
What are you doing?
(SUPER DUPER Snippet)
曲が入ってこない。あ、そっか。踊らしてよ
The song isn't getting through. Oh, right. Let me dance.
踊らしてあげてよ
Let her dance.
ここですね
Here it is.
ここ、はじめも大好きですよ
Hajime also loves this part.
おー！いっちゃん好き！
Oh! I love it the most!
うん、わかる。いっちゃん好き
Yeah, I get it. I love it the most.
奏も好き。え、5人一致ってことですね
Kanade likes it too. Oh, so all 5 agree.
5人一致でここのフレーズがいいと
All 5 agree this phrase is good.
なんか、ちゃんとさ、それこそ、うちらの色が出てるというか。
MANGAとかGENIUSとかそういう...
Like, it really brings out our colors.
Like 'MANGA' or 'GENIUS'...
ちゃんとこう、僕たちの歌ってる人に合ってる歌詞って感じが、
それこそちゃんと見てくださってるんだなって感じが...
It feels like the lyrics match the person singing,
and it feels like they're really watching us...
うん、わかる
Yeah, I get it.
めちゃめちゃ良かったですね
It was really good.
大虎さんさ、うちらの配信見てんのかな？
I wonder if Ohtora-san watches our streams?
えー！
Eh!
見てくれてるからこその、この解像度の作詞作曲なんじゃないの？
Isn't that why the lyrics and composition have such high resolution?
いや、確かに。これ見てなかったらなんか気まずいけどな
Yeah, certainly. It'd be a bit awkward if they didn't watch it.
その場合はカットで。生だけど。あ、生だから無理か
In that case, cut it. Even though it's live.
Ah, it's live so it's impossible.
ということで、続きまして、7曲目もユニット曲でございます。
So, moving on, the 7th song is also a unit song.
奏、はじめ二人の『LAKI MODE』の徹底解剖です！
It's a thorough analysis of "LAKI MODE" by Kanade and Hajime!
LAKI MODE! ヨオー！
LAKI MODE! Yo-oh!
え、LAKI MODE、どんな曲ですか？お二人どちらでもいいよ
So, what kind of song is LAKI MODE? Either of you is fine.
あ、LAKI MODEはですね。奏はこの曲は、
Ah, LAKI MODE is... I thought this song is...
君と歌やダンスを通じて喜びや感情を分かち合おう、
るんるん、みたいな楽曲なのかなと思いました
...about sharing joy and emotions through singing and dancing with you,
like "run-run".
あと楽曲の音的に、ReGLOSSの楽曲の中で一番キュートな曲かなと思ってて
Also, sound-wise, I think it's the cutest song among ReGLOSS's songs.
そういうイメージがあって、奏の中でもこの曲を歌う時には、
とにかくキュートに歌おうっていう気持ちがあります
I have that image, so when I sing this song,
I have a feeling of singing it as cutely as possible.
あと、なんていうかこの楽曲、ラップみたく畳み掛けるような
ラップパートがすごく多いので...
Also, how should I say, this song has many rap parts
that follow one after another like rap...
噛まないようにってすごく気をつけて歌ってます。
よかったら聴いてください
I'm very careful not to stumble over my words while singing.
Please listen to it.
流しちゃおうかな、流す。いいよ
Shall we play it? Let's play it. Go ahead.
じゃ、流します。お願いします。噛まないように
Then, I'll play it. Please listen. So I don't stumble...
(LAKI MODE Snippet)
めちゃめちゃこの曲好きで
I really like this song.
わかる、いいよね。めっちゃ何回も聴いた
I know, it's good. I listened to it many times.
これ、カラオケで歌ったんだけど、バカ難しくて、
絶対表じゃしばらく歌えません
I sang this at karaoke, but it was incredibly difficult,
I definitely can't sing it in public for a while.
そうなの？えー、難しい
Really? Eh, it's difficult.
LAKI MODEはさ、なんか軽やかさがあるよね
LAKI MODE has a certain lightness to it, doesn't it?
しかも、この二人の最高にいいところをこう抽出しました、
って感じで天才だと思った、マジで。溶け合うよね、二人の歌声が
And it feels like the best parts of these two were extracted,
I really thought it was genius. Their voices really melt together.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
あ、真ん中に入ってすみません。あー、いいぞ
Ah, sorry for getting in the middle. Ah, this is good.
はい、ということで、ここで秘蔵話いただいております
Okay, so we have some behind-the-scenes stories here.
こちらは褒め言葉、かつ楽曲のポイントでございますね。
こちらです。じゃじゃーん
These are compliments and also key points of the song.
Here they are. Ta-da!
お二人の歌唱力が高いので、言葉は詰め込み過ぎず
歌唱力が伝わる楽曲に仕上げてます
Since both of them have high singing ability,
I finished the song so that their singing ability is conveyed without cramming in too many words.
素晴らしい。素晴らしい
Wonderful. Wonderful.
ちょ、確かに。嬉しいね
Wait, certainly. I'm happy.
詰め込まれて
Being packed in,
通り100％のあれだとまだまだ足りなかったんで
if it were just the usual 100%, it wouldn't have been enough.
これからってこと？
You mean from now on?
本当はもっと何かあの、もうこう、ダダダダダッていうのがあったかもしれない。
Actually, there might have been even more of that "da-da-da-da-da" energy.
なるほど。なるほど。
I see. I see.
ちょっと1回聞いてみたいね、オートラさんに。全部詰め込んで、言葉詰め込んでみてくださいって。
I'd like to ask OHTORA-san once. To try and pack everything in, pack the words in.
えー、どうなっちゃうんだろう。
Oh, I wonder what that would turn out like.
奏端最高イェイイェイイェイ。
Kanade and Hajime are the best, yay yay yay.
止まらないよな。
They won't stop, will they?
でも確かに余韻のある部分もあるから、そういう箇所もちゃんと作って、こう、聞かせるみたいな曲にしたっていう意味なのかもね。
But certainly, there are parts with a lingering feel, so maybe it means making a song that highlights those spots.
素晴らしいですね。
That's wonderful.
確かに、なんか歌唱力っていうか、なんか面白い試みみたいなのはすごく感じて、
Indeed, I really felt like it was an interesting attempt, or rather a display of singing ability,
楽曲の中でなもなんか、
and even within the song...
「ice, ice」とか、
...like "ice, ice"...
そういうなんか、面白い発音を取り入れたりするところがすごいなんか、
...incorporating such interesting pronunciations really felt like...
遊び心というか、そういうのを感じました。
...a sense of playfulness.
番長はどうよ？好きなフレーズとかある？「LAKI MODE」で。
How about you, Banchou? Do you have any favorite phrases in "LAKI MODE"?
そりゃあね、「やみつきになるDance, dance、ハイになるまでIce, ice」やな。
Well, of course, "Addictive dance, dance, until you get high, ice, ice".
かわいい！
Cute!
これはなんか、みんな1回聞いたら「お、ここ、好き」ってなるよね。
This is something where once everyone hears it, they'll be like, "Oh, I like this part."
なる。なる。
Yeah. Yeah.
なんか耳に残るというか、言いたくなる感じやな。
It's like it sticks in your ears, or makes you want to say it.
好きやな。
I like it.
かわいい。
Cute.
いいですね。LAKI MODEね、ぜひ皆さんね、今回CD収録されておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
That's great. LAKI MODE is included on the CD this time, so please check it out.
配信もされてるんで！お願いします！聞いてね！
It's also being streamed! Please listen to it!
はい！ということで、7曲の紹介が終わったところで、
Yes! So, now that the introduction of the seven songs is over...
ここまでね、1年間歌ってきて、今さらこれ聞けないよとか、
...after singing for a year, there might be things you feel you can't ask about now...
ここを意味ちょっとよく分かんなかったけど聞けなかったみたいなこと皆さんありますよね。
...or things where you didn't quite understand the meaning but couldn't ask. You all have those, right?
結構ありますね。確かに。
Quite a few. Definitely.
いろいろありますが、なので、先ほどから何度か解説をしていただいているオートラさんに、
There are various things, so we...
インタビューをして私たちの疑問をぶつけてきました！
...interviewed OHTORA-san, who's been providing commentary, and brought him our questions!
何！すごい！
What! Amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
えー、どんな答えなのか、私たち一同もね、すごく楽しみにしております。それでは、よろしくお願いしまーす！
We are all very much looking forward to what kind of answers he has. Well then, please go ahead!
お願いします！
Please!
お、お、どうも。ReGLOSSの楽曲を制作担当しているオートラです。
Oh, hello. I'm OHTORA, in charge of producing ReGLOSS songs.
オートラさんだ！本物だ！
It's OHTORA-san! The real one!
さっきのものまね似てねーな。
That impression earlier wasn't like him at all.
聞いてみたいこと聞いていきます。よろしくお願いします。まず、私から。
I'll ask the things we want to know. Please. First, from me.
私たちの配信見てますか？
Are you watching our streams?
オートラさんが私たちの配信見てるのか、さっきもちょっと話題になりましたが、気になっておりまして。
I'm curious if OHTORA-san watches our streams, which was mentioned a bit earlier.
楽曲「SUPER DOOPER」の2番の歌詞とか、3人の配信にまつわるものでございましたから。
Since the lyrics of the second verse of "SUPER DOOPER" were related to the three of them's streams.
さてどうなんでしょう、と。疑問ぶつけてきました。私たちの配信を見ておりますでしょうか？
So, how is it? I've brought this question. Do you watch our streams?
グロッサー。
GLOSSER.
えー！すごい！
Eh! Amazing!
曲を書く上で彼女たちのこと結構理解しないと、自分の中から湧き出てこない。
When writing songs, if I don't understand them quite well, things won't well up from within me.
へー、すごいじゃん。
Wow, that's great.
はいはい。
Right, right.
OHTORAの推しは？
Who is OHTORA's oshi?
オ、で、ついでに推しも聞いちゃおうかな。推しは？
Oh, and while we're at it, let's ask who your oshi is. Who's your oshi?
誰だろうね。
I wonder who it is.
青くんの配信、面白い。
Ao-kun's streams are interesting.
青くんのさ、分かり手選手権みたいなの。
Like Ao-kun's "Wakarite Championship".
芸人じゃないと出来なくないかみたいな。
I thought, "Isn't this something only a comedian could do?"
カッコいい、カッコいい、魅惑のカッコいい感じ。それが最高、みたいなこと言ってくれてると思ったら全然違った。
I thought he'd say "Cool, cool, charming and cool. That's the best," but it was totally different.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
アーティストの上でだよね。
That's from an artist's perspective, right?
続いては奏、読んでもらっていいですか？
Next is Kanade, can you read yours?
瞬間ハートビートに出てくる「キミ」って誰の事？奏はReGLOSSのメンバーの事を言ってるのかと思ってます
Who is the "Kimi" in Shunkan Heartbeat? Kanade thinks it refers to ReGLOSS members.
はい。「瞬間ハートビート」に出てくる「キミ」って誰のこと？
Yes. Who is the "Kimi" that appears in "Shunkan Heartbeat"?
奏はReGLOSSのメンバーのこと言ってるのか、と思って歌ってたりするんですけど。
Kanade sings it thinking it refers to the ReGLOSS members...
オートラさんが想像してる「キミ」は誰なのか気になります。
...but I'm curious about who the "Kimi" OHTORA-san imagines is.
何度か出てくるよね、君のなんとかまで持った。
It comes up a few times, like "held until your..." something.
「キミ」って解釈の受け取り方は、
Regarding the interpretation of "Kimi"...
自分以外のメンバーのことでもいいですし、
...it can be the other members...
ファンのみんな、という意味でもあります。
...and it also means all the fans.
どちらの意味でも。受け取り方の解釈で、なんかいろいろ幅が広がるから。
It's both. Depending on the interpretation, it broadens the scope in various ways.
続きまして青くんですね。読んでもらっていいですか？バディーズについてです。
Next is Ao-kun. Can you read it? It's about "buddyz".
「buddy」ではなく「bvdiz」にした意図や読みづらくなってる理由など。
The intention behind using "bvdiz" instead of "buddy", etc.
はい。「buddy」ではなく「bvdiz」にした意図や読みづらくなってる理由など。
Yes. The intention behind using "bvdiz" instead of "buddy", and why it's harder to read, etc.
バディーズって正しくはこういう綴りだったりすると思うんですよ。「U」。
I think "Buddies" is correctly spelled like this, with a "U".
それをわざわざ「V」にしたってなんか独特な読み方してるけど、どんな意図があるのかな、と思って。
I wondered what the intention was for changing it to a "V" and giving it such a unique reading.
確かに気になる。最初読めなかったもんね。
It's certainly intriguing. We couldn't read it at first.
奏たちは今だに「ブブズ」って言ってます。聞きたいです。教えてください。
Kanade and the others still call it "Bubuz". We want to know. Please tell us.
なんか意図がね、ありそうですけれども。
It seems there might be some intention.
buddyの代わりにVを使ってるんですけど。
I'm using "V" instead of "buddy"...
Vの字面がグッとグッとで可愛いなと。
...because the visual shape of the "V" looks sharp and cute.
可愛い！
Cute!
遊び心を入れたタイトルにしたかった。なるほどね、ちょっと読みづらくして。
I wanted to make the title playful. I see, by making it a bit hard to read.
そういうの好き！
I like that!
確かに可愛い。いい遊び心ですね。
It's certainly cute. A nice sense of playfulness.
LAKI MODEのIceってどんな意味？
What does "Ice" in LAKI MODE mean?
続きまして、はじめ、読てもらっていいですか？
Next, Hajime, can you read yours?
はい。歌詞に「Ice, Ice」って出てくるんですけど、
Yes. "Ice, Ice" appears in the lyrics...
「Ice」ってどういう意味で使ってるのかな、って。
...and I wonder what "Ice" means here.
確かに。なんか海外のスラングとかでは「Ice」は宝石なんて意味もあったりするんですが、さあどうなんでしょうか？
True. In some foreign slang, "Ice" means jewelry, but I wonder how it is here.
宝石的なあれなのか、別の意味なのか。
Is it meant as a jewel, or is it another meaning?
スラングでIceってあるんですけど...
There is a slang term 'Ice'...
あんまりそっちの意味では入れてなくて。
but I didn't use it in that sense.
LAKI MODEの曲の世界観がなんかひんやりするような感じがする僕、最初聞いた時。
When I first heard it, the world of 'LAKI MODE' felt a bit chilly to me.
なのでIceって言葉を入れようかなっていうふうに思いました。
So I thought about including the word 'Ice'.
すご耳ざわりいいので。
It sounds very pleasant to the ear.
続きましてリリカ、お願いします。
Next, Ririka, please.
今後ReGLOSSでやってみたいなという楽曲があれば、ぜひ教えていただきたいです。
If there's a type of song you'd like to try with ReGLOSS, please let us know.
和メロというか、和を感じさせる曲を作りたい。
I'd like to make a song with a Japanese-style melody or feel.
おー、いい！いいじゃん！
Oh, nice! That sounds great!
シンメトリーでも結構和っぽいなって思ってた。
I thought Symmetry felt quite Japanese-style too.
この5人ならどこへでも行ける。
With these five, they can go anywhere.
さらにおめでとうございます。
Once again, congratulations.
ということで、ReGLOSSの楽曲制作をしていただいておりますオートラさんにお話を聞きました。ありがとうございました！
So, we've been talking to OHTORA-san, who's been producing ReGLOSS's songs. Thank you very much!
すごい機会だった。やっぱり今までにね...
It was a great opportunity. We haven't had the chance...
いろんな質問とかをさせていただく機会、まだなかったから。
to ask all these kinds of questions before.
私たちの謎が解剖されたね。
Our mysteries have been dissected.
これを聞いた上でもう一回聞き直したいかも！
Knowing this, I want to listen to them again!
聞き直したいので、アルバムをぜひ皆さん買ってください！
I want to re-listen, so everyone, please buy the album!
よろしくお願いします。配信もありますので。
Thank you. It's also available on streaming.
オートラさんが僕のプリンセスだって。
OHTORA-san said I'm his princess.
プリンセス！ありがとう。
Princess! Thank you.
僕、かっこいい？ありがとう、オートラさん。
Am I cool? Thank you, OHTORA-san.
次に進めていいですか？
May I move on?
ということで、ReGLOSSの楽曲制作にまつわるお話をしたところで...
So, now that we've talked about ReGLOSS's music production...
この後はアルバム発売記念のミニライブ、もうこの後すぐありますから...
there will be a mini-live commemorating the album release right after this...
楽しみに待っていてくださいね。
so please look forward to it.
それでは私たちはライブの準備をしますので。
We'll go get ready for the live.
一旦CMです！
We'll be right back after the commercials!
リグラス！
ReGLOSS!
1st ALBUM ReGLOSS 発売中！
1st ALBUM ReGLOSS Now on Sale!
リグラス！
ReGLOSS!
1st ALBUM ReGLOSS 発売中！
1st ALBUM ReGLOSS Now on Sale!
飛び乗って To the future
Flying start で All right Restart light
Jump on board, To the future
With a flying start, it's all right, Restart light
ときめいてしまえば
瞬く間に広がる解放区
Once my heart starts throbbing
The liberated zone expands in the blink of an eye
一つ一つ全てがドラマ
待ち侘びたデイ Restart light
Each and every moment is a drama
The day I've been waiting for, Restart light
代わる代わる彩るパノラマ
満ち溢れるフィーリンググラデーション
A panorama colored in turns
Overflowing feeling gradation
シンメトリー
Symmetry
無重力のような
Like weightlessness
恋焦がれて咲き乱れて
Burning with love, blooming in profusion
失いかけた夢の
The dream I was about to lose
続きを紡いでいこう
Let's continue to spin its tale
乾いた世界を満たしてメロディ
A melody to fill this parched world
Give your love 一身同体
Give your love, two hearts as one
Okay 君と重なるシンメトリー
Okay, symmetry overlapping with you
巧みに寄せ 朝陽の方へ
Skillfully drawing closer, towards the morning sun
泡沫メイビー
Utakata Maybe
回れ右今夜別れ道
About-face, tonight is the parting of ways
胸騒ぎレイニー
Restless rainy
繰り返しさよならため息
Repeating goodbyes and sighs
ほんのちょっとの間も停滞
Stagnant for even just a little while
くすぶったままの停滞を
The stagnation that remains smoldering
後ろ姿雲を過ごしていたい
I want to spend time like the clouds behind me
今はまだ見過ごしていたいよ
For now, I still want to overlook it
bvDIZ
ハイ皆様盛り上がってるかー！
Hey everyone, are you having a blast?!
Okay, Dokey 夜最高レバディ
Okey-dokey, best night ever!
Easy, Breezy 歌いだせパーフェクト
Easy, breezy, start singing perfectly
Favorite!
Okay, Dokey 夜最高レバディ
Okey-dokey, best night ever!
Easy, Breezy 歌いだせパーフェクト
Easy, breezy, start singing perfectly
Okay, Dokey このままでいたいよね
Okey-dokey, I want to stay like this
Easy, Breezy 踊ろうよエブリバディ
Easy, breezy, let's dance everybody
瞬間ハートビート
Shunkan Heartbeat
心奪われた
My heart was stolen
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
A whimsical moment, Heartbeat
ドラマチックの狭間
In between the drama
もう一人じゃない煌めく星
No longer alone, a sparkling star
描く未来予想図は
The future map I'm drawing
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
I want to pull the same dream closer
果てしない旅路の向こうに
Beyond the endless journey
間違いのない奇跡があるはず
There must be a miracle without a doubt
さよならメランコリー
Goodbye, melancholy
止められはしないこの衝動
This impulse cannot be stopped
突き進むだけさ
Just pushing forward
なりふり構わず Are you ready?
Regardless of appearances, are you ready?
限界はないさ準備を無限大の異次元
There are no limits, prepare for the infinite other dimension
一番目立つ煌めき夜空皆既して
The most prominent sparkle, eclipsing the night sky
喜びも悲しみも分かち合っていこう
Let's share both joy and sorrow
君とならどこまでも
With you, I can go anywhere
みんなーアルバム買ってねー！
Everyone, buy the album!
いっぱい聞いてねー！
Listen to it a lot!
聞いてねー！
Listen to it!
心に響きました！
It touched my heart!
ね、ReGLOSSみんなで頑張って行くぞ！
Right, let's do our best as ReGLOSS!
頑張るぞー！
Let's do our best!
オー！
Yeah!
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!
オッケー。
Okay.
いい感じー！
That felt good!
瞬間ハートビートと、シンメトリー、泡沫メイビー、フィーリングラデーション、bvDIZのサビメドレーでお送りしましたー！
We presented a chorus medley of "Shunkan Heartbeat", "Symmetry", "Utakata Maybe", "Feeling Gradation", and "bvDIZ"!
ファーストアルバム「ReGLOSS」は全国のCDショップでお求めいただけます。
Our 1st album "ReGLOSS" is available at CD shops nationwide.
そしてさらに、各種音楽配信サービスでもお聴きいただけます！
And what's more, it's also available on various music streaming services!
ReGLOSSが歩んできた1年間のストーリーをこの1枚にギュッと詰め込んでおりますので...
The story of ReGLOSS's first year is packed into this one album...
ぜひぜひたくさん聴いていただけたら嬉しいです！
...so we'd be very happy if you'd listen to it many times!
追加でお知らせがございます！
We have some additional announcements!
まずは新商品についてです。
First, about new products.
10月28日月曜日より、シンメトリーのイラストを使った新しいアクリルスタンドの、「ReGLOSS ストリーミングアクリルスタンド」を販売しております！
From Monday, Oct 28th, we are selling new acrylic stands using the "Symmetry" illustrations, the "ReGLOSS Streaming Acrylic Stands"!
フレームデザインのパーツが一緒についていて、前後で入れ替え可能なのでいろんな飾り方ができますよ。
They come with frame design parts that can be swapped front and back, so you can display them in many ways.
また、「ReGLOSS's PLAYLIST re-recording」が好評発売中！
Also, "ReGLOSS's PLAYLIST re-recording" is now on sale!
こちらは昨年実施の「ホロライブプロダクション オフィシャルショップ in 東京駅」で販売した一部商品の再ラインナップとなります。
This is a re-release of some products sold at the "hololive production Official Shop in Tokyo Station" last year.
最近ReGLOSSを知ってくださった方は、特にぜひぜひちょっと手に取っていただきたい、チェックしていただきたいと思います。
For those who have recently discovered ReGLOSS, I especially want you to check them out.
そして、12月29日にKT Zepp Yokohamaで開催する「ReGLOSS Room Next Stage 公開録音 年末スペシャル」の2次先行が、明日12時から...
And the second round of lottery for "ReGLOSS Room Next Stage Public Recording Year-end Special" at KT Zepp Yokohama on Dec 29th starts tomorrow at 12:00...
お昼の12時からかな？ スタートします。皆さんぜひ会場に遊びに来てください！
Starting from noon? Please come and visit us at the venue!
「hololive friends with u to go」のReGLOSSもなんと本日発売です！
The ReGLOSS version of "hololive friends with u to go" is also released today!
ホロライブプロダクション公式オンラインショップ、または全国のHMV、HMV&BOOKSの店舗さんでもお買い求めいただけますので、ぜひぜひゲットしてください！
You can buy them at the hololive production official online shop, or at HMV and HMV&BOOKS stores nationwide, so please get yours!
お願いします。えーそして、このあと20時から...
Please. And then, from 20:00...
わたくし儒烏風亭らでんのチャンネルで...
On my, Juufuutei Raden's channel...
えー、初めて奏とらでんで歌いました
So, the song that Kanade and I sang together
『千年生きてる』プレミア公開でございます！
for the first time, "Sennen Ikiteru," is premiering!
ぜひよろしくお願いします！
Please be sure to check it out!
このあとすぐです！
It starts right after this!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
よろしくー！
Check it out!
それでは、本日はありがとうございました！
Well then, thank you very much for today!
ReGLOSSでした！
We were ReGLOSS!
さようならー！
Goodbye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
この人、裏で、さっき攻撃してきました！
This person attacked me backstage just now!
攻撃したー！
I attacked her!
こら！あ！
Hey! Ah!
攻撃されたー！
I got attacked back!